<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DevOps Trainings &amp; Consulting - bee42 solutions gmbh</title><link>https://bee42.com/en/</link><description>Recent content on DevOps Trainings &amp; Consulting - bee42 solutions gmbh</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>de</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bee42.com/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Manager Media Production Systems (ProSiebenSat.1 Produktion GmbH)</title><link>https://bee42.com/en/testimonials/stephan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bee42.com/en/testimonials/stephan/</guid><description>Through the intensive and instructive in-house Kubernetes training we were able to prepare our DevOps team excellently for the operation of our Kubernetes cluster. With the help of the training we were able to learn the basics of Kubernetes, recognize many obstacles and reach our goal faster.</description></item><item><title>LIMETEC Biotechnologies GmbH</title><link>https://bee42.com/en/testimonials/tuncer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bee42.com/en/testimonials/tuncer/</guid><description>The container DevOps Camp was super organized and prepared. Thanks to the training, I was able to bring Docker&amp;rsquo;s broad scope of application to my attention and gain experience in administration. In addition, I was able to weigh the advantages and disadvantages of the various applications for my own application and plan accordingly my goals better. I particularly liked that the training was flexible in answering individual questions and suggested solutions in the group.</description></item><item><title>Freelancer</title><link>https://bee42.com/en/testimonials/richter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bee42.com/en/testimonials/richter/</guid><description>At the Container DevOps Camp each topic was introduced with a brief theoretical part and afterwards put into practice immediately. This enabled active collaboration without the theoretical persistence of other lectures. The knowledge was thus immediately consolidated and also usable. The small group was very good for learning.</description></item><item><title>Hosting of BRVZ GmbH (IT Consulting of the STRABAG SE)</title><link>https://bee42.com/en/testimonials/kleinsasser/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bee42.com/en/testimonials/kleinsasser/</guid><description>The trainer Niclas was able to answer all our questions about CI / CD / CD and gave us ideas and approaches on how to solve certain requirements in our environment. There were also some tools mentioned at the edge of the training, which have helped us in some cases or will help in the future. Also for our development we could take a lot with us in relation to Git, GitLab and &amp;ldquo;best practices&amp;rdquo;.</description></item></channel></rss>