<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bee42 solutions gmbh</title>
    <link>https://bee42.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on bee42 solutions gmbh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 22:27:32 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bee42.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>docker for java lab</title>
      <link>https://bee42.com/trainings/docker-for-java-lab-de/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 22:27:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bee42.com/trainings/docker-for-java-lab-de/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please click here for an &lt;a href=&#34;https://bee42.com/trainings/docker-for-java-lab&#34;&gt;english version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Docker und das spannende Ökosystem ist sehr hilfreich für jeden Java-Entwickler. Diese Lab gibt einen Überblick über die besten Praktiken für die Entwicklung von Java-Anwendungen mit Docker. Das Docker-Ökosystem bietet Dir vielversprechende Tools zum Paketieren Deiner Software, Wiederverwendung vorhandener Services, Datenbanken oder Tools. Docker hilft, Deine Continuous Integration Pipeline voranzutreiben. Aber, ein gutes Java-Image aufzubauen und Deine Container direkt in der Produktion zu verwenden, ist eine Herausforderung. Bündeln Deine Java-Software, teste Deine Dienste mit Docker und befähige Deine Entwicklung zu mehr Qualiät. Dieses Labor gibt Dir einige nützliche Hinweise und diskutieren Tricks, um Docker nahtlos mit Java zu verwenden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tag-eins-br-baue-deine-java-microservices-mit-docker&#34;&gt;Tag Eins: &lt;br&gt;Baue Deine Java Microservices mit Docker&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker Basics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Empower Deine Entwicklung mit Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aufbauen einer Spring Boot Microservices mit Maven&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verpacken der Java Anwendung mit Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Erzeugen eines Databank Container&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TDD mit Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Baue ein eigenes Java Base Images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debugging mit Java im Container&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker IDE Unterstützung&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tag-zwei-br-java-für-die-produktion&#34;&gt;Tag Zwei: &lt;br&gt;Java für die Produktion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Denke Deine Infrastruktur zuerst&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatische Erzeugung Deiner Image Build mit einer CI-Pipeline&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Baue Deine eigene  Werkzeugkette: Java, Maven, Tomcat, &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Erzeugen eines optimale Java Werkzeugkastens mit Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beachte die &lt;strong&gt;12 Factor Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skalliere Deine Java Microservices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Java Micorservices in der Produktion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integiere Metriken und Logging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;voraussetzungen-und-leistungen&#34;&gt;Voraussetzungen und Leistungen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;zielgruppe-wer-sollte-teilnehmen&#34;&gt;Zielgruppe/ Wer sollte teilnehmen?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Java Entwickler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software- und Systemarchitekten&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;voraussetzungen-an-die-teilnehmer&#34;&gt;Voraussetzungen an die Teilnehmer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gute Kenntnisse Java, Maven, Spring boot&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grundkenntnisse Microservices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grundkenntnisse Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grundkenntnisse Linux (Debian, bash, vim, curl, network, packages)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;leistungen&#34;&gt;Leistungen&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verpflegung: Frühstück, Mittagessen und Getränke (nicht alkoholisch)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Schulungsmaterialien&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nicht enthalten: Hotel Übernachtungen, Anreise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rechner werden nicht gestellt, das eigene Notebook muss mitgebracht werden.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imprint</title>
      <link>https://bee42.com/Imprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 19:26:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bee42.com/Imprint/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;legal-information&#34;&gt;Legal information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Legal information that is necessary for a German site &lt;br/&gt;
Information required under § 5 Para. 1 of the German Telemedia Act:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bee42 solutions gmbh&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;
Peter Rossbach (Geschäftsführer)&lt;br&gt;
Am Josephsschacht 72&lt;br&gt;
D-44879 Bochum&lt;br&gt;
Germany&lt;br&gt;
Email: &lt;a href=&#34;info@bee42.com&#34;&gt;info@bee42.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Phone +49(0)157-72 54 92 63&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Responsible for the content according to § 55 Abs. 2 RStV:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter Rossbach (Geschäftsführer)&lt;br&gt;
Am Josephsschacht 72&lt;br&gt;
D-44879 Bochum&lt;br&gt;
Germany&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VAT-ID according to §27 a Umsatzsteuergesetz: DE284932374&lt;br&gt;
Number in the commercial register HR B 14047&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>42... and the meaning of life - bee42</title>
      <link>https://bee42.com/42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bee42.com/42/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;42-and-the-meaning-of-life&#34;&gt;42 … and the meaning of life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;42 is the answer given to the question posed by Douglas Adams in the novel &amp;ldquo;A Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy&amp;rdquo; about life, the universe and everything. According to this question of humanity, the answer was calculated from the largest existing computer at the time and is accurate with absolute certainty. But nothing is to be done because nobody knows what the question is. According to the protagonist Prak, the knowledge of question and answer is mutually exclusive. It is impossible to ever know both of them in the same universe - and if it does happen, questions and answers will be mutually canceled and the universe will be taken, which will then be replaced by something even more bizarre and incomprehensible. Some believe this has already happened&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;42 is thus the meaning of life, and the answer to everything. This can then be interpreted differently: everything is the meaning of life, or that life makes no sense. However, everyone has to find an answer for himself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Allgemeine Geschaeftsbedingungen</title>
      <link>https://bee42.com/agb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bee42.com/agb/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please find the english Terms and Conditions &lt;a href=&#34;#english-version&#34;&gt;below&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;allgemeine-geschäftsbedingungen&#34;&gt;Allgemeine Geschäftsbedingungen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mit Ihrer Anmeldung zu einem bee42 solutions GmbH Training und Workshop werden die nachfolgenden Teilnahmebedingungen Vertragsgegenstand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitte lesen Sie sich diese Bedingungen deshalb in Ruhe durch!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;geltungsbereich&#34;&gt;Geltungsbereich&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Veranstalter der Trainings und Workshops ist die bee42 solutions GmbH, Am Josephsschacht 72 D-44879 Bochum, (nachfolgend bee42 genannt).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Es gelten für die Teilnahme an einem bee42-Training die nachstehend formulierten “Allgemeinen Bedingungen für bee42-Trainings und -Workshops”,
die die Vertragsbasis zwischen bee42 und einem/einer Teilnehmer/in verbindlich regeln.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Es gilt die zum Zeitpunkt der Anmeldung gültige Fassung dieser Bedingungen. Die deutsche Version geht im Falle eines Widerspruchs oder sonstiger Abweichungen sowie bei Streit über die Auslegung des Vertrages zwischen diesen beiden Versionen vor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Von den “Allgemeinen Bedingungen für bee42-Trainings und -Workshops” abweichende Formulierungen werden von bee42 nicht anerkannt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;widerrufsrecht-für-verbraucher&#34;&gt;Widerrufsrecht für Verbraucher&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bee42-Trainings und bee42-Workshops richten sich an Unternehmer. Für den Fall, dass sich ein Verbraucher laut Konsumentenschutzgesetz für ein bee42-Trainings und bee42-Workshops anmeldet, so gilt zusätzlich zu den hier formulierten “Allgemeinen Bedingungen für bee42-Trainings und -Workshops” das folgende Widerrufsrecht für Verbraucher laut Konsumentenschutzgesetz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Widerrufsbelehrung für Verbraucher laut Konsumentenschutzgesetz&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wenn Sie Verbraucher laut Konsumentenschutzgesetz sind, haben Sie ergänzend zu den “Allgemeinen Bedingungen für bee42-Trainings und -Workshops” das folgende Widerrufsrecht.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;widerrufsbelehrung&#34;&gt;Widerrufsbelehrung&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;a.&lt;/strong&gt; Widerrufsrecht&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sie können Ihre Vertragserklärung innerhalb von 30 Tagen nach Erhalt einer Anmeldebestätigung durch bee42 ohne Angabe von Gründen in Textform (z. B. Brief oder E-Mail) widerrufen.
Zur Wahrung der Widerrufsfrist genügt die rechtzeitige Absendung des Widerrufs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Der Widerruf ist zu richten an:
bee42 solutions GmbH
Am Josephsschacht 72
44879 Bochum
E-Mail: info@bee42.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;b.&lt;/strong&gt; Widerrufsfolgen&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Im Falle eines wirksamen Widerrufs sind die beiderseits empfangenen Leistungen zurückzugewähren und ggf. gezogene Nutzun­gen (z.B. Zinsen) herauszugeben.
Können Sie uns die empfangene Leistung ganz oder teilweise nicht oder nur in verschlechtertem Zustand zurückgewähren, müssen Sie uns insoweit ggf. Wertersatz leisten. Dies kann dazu führen, dass Sie die vertraglichen Zahlungsverpflichtungen für den Zeitraum bis zum Widerruf gleichwohl erfüllen müssen. Verpflichtungen zur Erstattung von Zahlun­gen müssen innerhalb von 30 Tagen erfüllt werden. Die Frist beginnt für Sie mit der Absendung Ihrer Widerrufserklärung, für uns mit deren Empfang.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c.&lt;/strong&gt; Besondere Hinweise&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ihr Widerrufsrecht erlischt vorzeitig, wenn der Vertrag von beiden Seiten auf Ihren ausdrücklichen Wunsch vollständig erfüllt ist, bevor Sie Ihr Widerrufsrecht ausgeübt haben.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ende der Widerrufsbelehrung&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;preisangaben&#34;&gt;Preisangaben&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soweit im Einzelnen nicht anders spezifiziert, erfolgt eine Preisangabe für ein bee42-Training oder einen bee42-Workshop als Nettopreis.
Sofern ein Teilnehmer zum Vorsteuerabzug berechtigt ist, kann er anhand der von uns bezifferten deutschen Umsatzsteuer erkennen, welche Beträge auf den ausgestellten Rechnungen ausgewiesen werden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Es gilt die deutsche Umsatzsteuer in Höhe von derzeit 19 Prozent, die im Bruttopreis enthalten ist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;teilnahmevoraussetzungen&#34;&gt;Teilnahmevoraussetzungen&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Das Vertragsverhältnis zwischen bee42 und dem Teilnehmer entspricht dem Charakter eines Beratungsvertrages, also eines Dienstvertrages.
Es werden keinerlei Versprechungen gemacht und es gibt keinerlei Garantien oder zu erreichende Ziele.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Die in den jeweiligen Training- oder Workshop-Beschreibungen genannten Teilnahmevoraussetzungen sind verbindlich und müssen auf jeden Fall eingehalten werden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;buchung-widerruf-oder-stornierung&#34;&gt;Buchung, Widerruf oder Stornierung&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;a.&lt;/strong&gt; Die Anmeldung zu einem bee42-Training oder einem bee42-Workshop kann per E-Mail oder via Internetformular erfolgen.
Nach Zugang einer Anmeldung wird diese von bee42 schriftlich bestätigt. Ein Teilnehmer erhält innerhalb von 10 Tagen nach seiner Anmeldung seine Rechnung.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;b.&lt;/strong&gt; Ein Teilnehmer kann seine Anmeldung vor Beginn einer bee42 Veranstaltung widerrufen.
 Bei Widerruf oder Stornierung der Anmeldung werden keinerlei zusätzliche Gebühren erhoben, sofern Widerruf oder Stornierung spätestens 14 Tage nach dem auf der Rechnung ausgewiesenen Rechnungsdatum erfolgen.
 Bei Widerruf oder Stornierung der Anmeldung nach den besagten 14 Tagen muss der Teilnehmer 50% des Bruttopreises tragen, sofern Widerruf oder Stornierung spätestens 30 Tage vor Veranstaltungsbeginn erfolgen.
 Im Falle einer späteren Absage oder bei Nichterscheinen wird dem Teilnehmer seitens bee42 der vollständige Bruttopreis für die Teilnahme in Rechnung gestellt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c.&lt;/strong&gt; Die Stornierung bedarf der Textform. Der Nachweis für die Absendung der Stornierung obliegt dem Stornierenden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fälligkeit-und-zahlung&#34;&gt;Fälligkeit und Zahlung&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sofern nicht anders angegeben, muss der Zahlungseingang des Rechnungsbetrages spätestens 14 Tage vor Veranstaltungsbeginn auf dem bee42-Konto ohne Abzug erfolgt sein. Nur eine vollständig und rechtzeitig bezahlte Rechnung berechtigt zur Teilnahme an Training oder Workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Der Teilnehmer erhält eine Rechnung mit ausgewiesener Mehrwertsteuer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;trainingsort&#34;&gt;Trainingsort&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Der Ort und die Zeiten für bee42-Trainings und bee42-Workshops ist in der jeweiligen Beschreibung angegeben.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;leistungsumfang&#34;&gt;Leistungsumfang&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Der Leistungsumfang eines bee42-Training oder -Workshops umfasst die Teilnahme am Training sowie die in der jeweiligen Beschreibung angegebenen Speisen und Getränke. Nicht im Preis inbegriffen sind die Übernachtungskosten sowie Anreise- und Abreisekosten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;trainingsabweichungen&#34;&gt;Trainingsabweichungen&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bee42 behält sich vor, Inhalte geringfügig zu ändern, um so stets aktuelle Inhalte anbieten zu können.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;änderung-des-veranstaltungsortes&#34;&gt;Änderung des Veranstaltungsortes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bee42 behält sich vor, aufgrund von Teilnehmerzahlen oder anderen wichtigen Gründen den Veranstaltungsort zu ändern. Es gilt dabei, dass nicht mehr als 20 km Entfernung zwischen ursprünglichem und neuem Veranstaltungsort liegen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;absage-einer-bee42-veranstaltung&#34;&gt;Absage einer bee42-Veranstaltung&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bee42 behält sich das Recht vor, ein Training oder einen Workshop abzusagen.
Bereits vom Teilnehmer vor der Absage bezahlte Gebühren werden in voller Höhe zurückerstattet. Für weitere Aufwendungen oder sonstige Nachteile, die dem Teilnehmer durch die Absage entstehen, kommt bee42 nicht auf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;copyright&#34;&gt;Copyright&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alle Rechte, auch die der Übersetzung, des Nachdrucks und der Vervielfältigung der Training- oder Workshop-Unterlagen oder Teilen daraus, bleiben bee42 vorbehalten.
Die Unterlagen oder Teile davon, dürfen ohne unsere schriftliche Genehmigung in keinster Weise reproduziert oder unter Verwendung elektronischer Systeme verarbeitet, vervielfältigt oder verbreitet werden. Eine Ausnahme bilden die Quellcodes der in den Trainings erarbeiteten Beispiel-Anwendungen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;haftung-und-gewährleistung&#34;&gt;Haftung und Gewährleistung&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alle Trainings und Workshops werden von bee42 mit größtmöglicher Sorgfalt vorbereitet und durchgeführt.
Eine Haftung für den Training oder Workshop-Erfolg sowie eine Haftung, die nicht auf Vorsatz oder grober Fahrlässigkeit beruht, werden ausgeschlossen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeder persönliche Einsatz der vermittelten Informationen erfolgt ausschließlich in Eigenverantwortung eines Teilnehmers.
Für jedwede Veränderung im persönlichen Leben oder Umfeld des Teilnehmers übernimmt bee42 keine Haftung.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;datenschutz&#34;&gt;Datenschutz&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Der sorgfältige und gewissenhafte Umgang mit den persönlichen Informationen und Daten des Teilnehmers ist uns wichtig.
Deshalb geben wir keine Daten an unbeteiligte Dritte weiter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeder Teilnehmer erklärt sich mit der elektronischen Verarbeitung seiner persönlichen Daten durch bee42 einverstanden, soweit dies zum Zwecke einer ordnungsgemäßen Training- und Workshopverwaltung und -durchführung erforderlich ist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;anwendbares-recht-und-schlussbestimmungen&#34;&gt;Anwendbares Recht und Schlussbestimmungen&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Es gilt das Recht der Bundesrepublik Deutschland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Die Bestimmungen des UN-Kauf- oder Vertragsrechts finden keine Anwendung.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Der Gerichtsstand für alle Streitigkeiten aus diesem Vertrag ist Bochum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sollten einzelne Bestimmungen dieser “Allgemeinen Bedingungen für bee42-Trainings und -Workshops” ganz oder teilweise unwirksam sein oder werden, so wird hierdurch die Gültigkeit der übrigen Bestimmungen nicht berührt.
Die ganz oder teilweise unwirksame Regelung soll durch eine Regelung ersetzt werden, deren wirtschaftlicher Erfolg dem der Unwirksamen möglichst nahe kommt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stand&lt;/strong&gt;: 19. Dezember 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;english-version&#34;/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;../terms-and-conditions&#34;&gt;English Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevOps Gathering 2017</title>
      <link>https://bee42.com/conferences/devops_gathering_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bee42.com/conferences/devops_gathering_2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The DevOps Gathering is an international conference located in Bochum - surrounded by the metropolitan area of the Ruhr Valley. This melting pot of past times industrial revolutions is nowadays a hot spot for Germany’s IT industry - a perfect place to discuss the next big revolution of our industry, the DevOps revolution. Let’s discuss the hot topics inside the DevOps community and start talking about
Docker, Kubernetes, Microservices, Clouds and everything else regarding DevOps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bee42 solutions gmbh are hosting a non-profit conference striving for high-quality content and providing a platform for experienced international speakers at the G DATA Campus in the heart of Bochum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pre-conference-workshops-march-23-2017&#34;&gt;Pre-Conference-Workshops - March 23, 2017&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venue:&lt;/strong&gt; Veranstaltungszentrum RUB, Universitätsstraße 150, 44801 Bochum&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Docker Workshops are an perfect fit for DevOps Engineers. Attendees have the chance to learn from some exciting Docker Captains and Experts. The concept of the workshop is to leave room for experiments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning Docker on a Raspberry Pi ARM-Cluster (Dieter Reuter and Peter Rossbach)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automated container building with GitLab/CI (Niclas Mietz)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker and Kubernetes for Java Developers (Roland Huss)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Bootiful&amp;rdquo; Containers with Spring-Boot and Docker (Kevin Wittek and Matthias Rottländer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting started with Docker on Windows Server 2016 (Stefan Scherer and Dieter Reuter)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Running Docker Containers on AWS (Philipp Garbe)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conference-talks-march-24-2017&#34;&gt;Conference Talks - March 24, 2017&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venue:&lt;/strong&gt; G Data Campus, Königsallee 178b, 44799 Bochum&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attendees obtain interesseting stories from Experts with different knowledge areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How we run Kubernetes in Kubernetes, aka Kubeception (Timo Derstappen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker Container Loading (Roland Huss)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting the most out of your containerized database (Claus Matzinger)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One year monitoring a small startup with Prometheus: lessons learned (Maykel Moya)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build and deploy multiarch Linux and Windows Container images (Stefan Scherer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intel and ARM, let Kubernetes rule them all! (Lucas Käldström)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make load-balancing great again with Træfik! (Emile Vauge and Manuel Laufenberg)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker Orchestration and Swarming (Peter Rossbach)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keynote: DevOps is not enough - towards a DevOps ecosystem (Uwe Friedrichsen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;container-open-space-march-25-2017&#34;&gt;Container Open Space - March 25, 2017&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Open Space format perfectly fits to the fast moving development of the Container ecosystem. It offers participants and experts the opportunity to launch discussions, address questions and challenges regarding Docker, Kubernetes and Cloud technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An Open Space is a simple and productive way for hosting conferences. Participants and experts will create and manage together their own agenda of parallel working sessions. The goal of this Open Space is to allow attendees to interact with one another and learn from each other – all under the guidance of an experienced moderator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Register and get one of our limited tickets, now!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io&#34;&gt;Get your Ticket&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker DevOps Camp</title>
      <link>https://bee42.com/trainings/docker-devops-camp-de/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bee42.com/trainings/docker-devops-camp-de/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please click here for an &lt;a href=&#34;https://bee42.com/trainings/docker-devops-camp&#34;&gt;english version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ob kleine Startups oder große Firmen – schon aufregend viele Unternehmen setzen auf die Open-Source-Technologie Docker. Die Container-Technologie rollt gerade den Virtualisierungsmarkt auf und verändert die Softwareentwicklung nachhaltig. Docker verspricht einen schnellen Start, flexible Konfiguration und stabile Images für Entwicklung und Produktion. In diesem Docker DevOps Camp wollen wir diesem Versprechen praktisch nachgehen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wir starten mit einem Überblick und stellen die ersten Schritte beim Einsatz von Docker vor. Du lernst die wichtigsten Befehle, Anweisungen und Konzepte praktisch kennen. Anhand eines ausführlichen Beispiels lernst Du, wie ein Microservice implementiert, mit Docker installiert und in einer Umgebung mit anderen Services integriert wird. Außerdem diskutieren wir das aktuelle Docker-Ökosystem und klären über Chancen und Risiken auf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dieses Camp vermittelt Dir die Docker-Grundlagen in nachvollziehbaren Schritten und versetzt Dich in die Lage anschließend selbst zu entscheiden, ob und wie Docker in Deinem Unternehmens- und IT-Kontext sinnvoll einsetzt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tag-eins-br-docker-grundlagen&#34;&gt;Tag Eins: &lt;br&gt;Docker Grundlagen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker Grundlagen und Installation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Container Technologie Grundlagen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kernel- vs Classical- Virtualisierung&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker Architektur&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Einsatzgebiete und mehr&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starten der Docker-Umgebung&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Images, Container und Registry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;einfache-nutzung&#34;&gt;Einfache Nutzung&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let’s run, stop and maintain containers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker CLI command übersicht&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Baue Deine Images auf der Basis eines Dockerfiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Build, Ship and Run”-Zyklus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker Tooling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Volume Management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network Management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logging und Metriken&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backup/Restore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Container Typen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tag-zwei-br-microservices-mit-docker&#34;&gt;Tag Zwei: &lt;br&gt; Microservices mit Docker&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;microservices&#34;&gt;Microservices&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think infrastructure first&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Erstellen einer einfachen Spring Boot App&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bau einer Toolchain mittels Java and Maven&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker für Java-Entwickler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Erstellung Database Container&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Empower your Development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;infrastruktur&#34;&gt;Infrastruktur&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aufbau der Microservice Infrastruktur&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Erzeuge eine einfache Build Pipeline&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nutzen von Service Discovery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Erzeuge Multi Host Networks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker Tipps &amp;amp; Tricks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tag-drei-br-skalierung-des-service-mit-docker-swarm&#34;&gt;Tag Drei: &lt;br&gt; Skalierung des Service mit Docker Swarm&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;swarming&#34;&gt;Swarming&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skalieren Sie Ihren Services mit Docker Swarming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update, Fehlererkennung und Redeployment von Services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mesh Network und Service Discovery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Einrichten eines Ingress Loadbalancer (traefik, haproxy od. nginx)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup Logging und Monitoring Systeme

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ELK-Stack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prometheus und Grafana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debuging Deines Containers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;go-to-production&#34;&gt;Go to production&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker für die Produktion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Erzeuge High-Quality Images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker Security Grundlagen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plugins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tipps und Tricks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review Best Practices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker on ARM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;voraussetzungen-und-leistungen&#34;&gt;Voraussetzungen und Leistungen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;zielgruppe-wer-sollte-teilnehmen&#34;&gt;Zielgruppe/ Wer sollte teilnehmen?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DevOps Entwickler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Administratoren&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software- und Systemarchitekten&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;voraussetzungen-an-die-teilnehmer&#34;&gt;Voraussetzungen an die Teilnehmer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grundkenntnisse Linux (Debian, bash, vim, curl, network, Virtualisierung)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grundkenntnisse Build- und Package-Systeme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grundkenntnisse Microservices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;leistungen&#34;&gt;Leistungen&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verpflegung: Frühstück, Mittagessen und Getränke (nicht alkoholisch)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Schulungsmaterialien&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nicht enthalten: Hotel Übernachtungen, Anreise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rechner werden nicht gestellt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Gitlab/CI Lab</title>
      <link>https://bee42.com/trainings/docker-gilab-ci-lab-de/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bee42.com/trainings/docker-gilab-ci-lab-de/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please click here for an &lt;a href=&#34;https://bee42.com/trainings/docker-gitlab-ci-lab&#34;&gt;english version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ob kleine Startups oder große Firmen – schon aufregend viele Unternehmen setzen auf die Open-Source-Technologie Docker. Die Container-Technologie rollt gerade den Virtualisierungsmarkt auf und verändert die Softwareentwicklung nachhaltig. Docker verspricht einen schnellen Start, flexible Konfiguration und stabile Images für Entwicklung und Produktion. In diesem Docker Lab wollen wir praktisch den Bau von Docker Images mit GITLAB/CI erleichtern und lernen gute Images zu fertigen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schön und gut, aber ein Entwickler oder Operator muss seine Automatisierung erst einmal bauen, einrichten und testen, damit Docker Images erstellt werden können. Bei dieser Schulung lernst Du, GitLab / CI einzurichten, um Deine Projekte zu pflegen und die Pipeline für Continuous Integration und Delivery für Docker-Images zu automatisieren.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wir beginnen mit einem Überblick von vorhandenen Techniken. In einer folgenden Einführung werden erste Schritte für den Einsatz von GitLab / CI erprobt. Du lernst dabei die wichtigsten Komponenten, Anleitungen und Konzepte kennen. Mit einem detaillierten Beispiel lernst Du, wie Du einen Microservice implementierst, den Build mit verschiedenen Gitlab Runner automatisierst, mit Docker installierst und diesen mit anderen Diensten in einer Umgebung testen und integrieren kannst. Wir zeigen Dir dein Image in deiner Umgebung einzusetzen. Darüber hinaus stellen wir vor, wie Du Builds auslösen kannst, gute Docker-Images erstellen und Images an Deine Docker-Registry versenden kannst.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tag-eins-br-gitlab-ci-grundlagen&#34;&gt;Tag Eins: &lt;br&gt; GITLAB / CI GRUNDLAGEN&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;einführung&#34;&gt;Einführung&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Was ist GitLab und was es nicht ist?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installation der GitLab Instance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Überblick über die GitLab Architektur&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detaillierte Übersicht über die GitLab Komponenten&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Richte verschiedene GitLab-Komponenten ein&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitLab UI-Übersicht&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check-in von einem einfachen Projekt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;workflow-mit-ihren-images-von-gitlab&#34;&gt;WORKFLOW MIT IHREN IMAGES VON GITLAB&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wir bauen und testen Docker-Images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Schiebe erfolgreich gebaute Images in die Registry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Erstelle eigene Images auf der Basis eines Dockerfiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Erstelle eigene GitLab Runner mit verschiedenen Typen

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker in Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker machine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSH&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;achte-auf-deine-gitlab-infrastruktur&#34;&gt;ACHTE AUF DEINE GITLAB-INFRASTRUKTUR&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protokollierung und Überwachung der GitLab Infrastruktur&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sichern und Wiederherstellen von Images aus GitLab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tag-2-br-erstellen-eines-geprüftes-microservice-mit-docker-und-gitlab&#34;&gt;Tag 2: &lt;br&gt; ERSTELLEN EINES GEPRÜFTES MICROSERVICE MIT DOCKER UND GITLAB&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;microservices&#34;&gt;Microservices&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Erstelle eine einfache Spring-Boot Application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Erstelle eine Toolchain für Anwendungsentwicklung (Java und Maven)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anwendungsentwicklung mit Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aufteilen von Microservices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microservice in einem Produktivsystem mit einem Delivery Concept einbinden&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gitlab-ci-tipps-und-tricks&#34;&gt;GITLAB / CI TIPPS UND TRICKS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pflege GitLab mit wenigen Schritten&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aktualisieren der Installation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sichern und Wiederherstellen der Installation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skaliere Deine CI-CD-Pipeline mit verschiedenen Konzepten&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;voraussetzungen-und-leistungen&#34;&gt;Voraussetzungen und Leistungen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;zielgruppe-wer-sollte-teilnehmen&#34;&gt;Zielgruppe/ Wer sollte teilnehmen?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DevOps Entwickler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Administratoren&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software- und Systemarchitekten&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;voraussetzungen-an-die-teilnehmer&#34;&gt;Voraussetzungen an die Teilnehmer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grundkenntnisse Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grundkenntnisse Linux (Debian, bash, vim, curl, network, Virtualisierung)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grundkenntnisse Java, Maven und SpringBoot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grundkenntnisse Microservices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;leistungen&#34;&gt;Leistungen&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verpflegung: Frühstück, Mittagessen und Getränke (nicht alkoholisch)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Schulungsmaterialien&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nicht enthalten: Hotel Übernachtungen, Anreise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rechner werden nicht gestellt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34; class=&#34;more page open-form&#34; data-form=&#34;docker-camp&#34;&gt;Book now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Prometheus Lab</title>
      <link>https://bee42.com/trainings/docker-prometheus-lab-de/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bee42.com/trainings/docker-prometheus-lab-de/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please click here for an &lt;a href=&#34;https://bee42.com/trainings/docker-prometheus-lab&#34;&gt;english version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ob kleine Startups oder große Firmen – schon aufregend viele Unternehmen setzen auf die Open-Source-Technologie Docker. Die Container-Technologie rollt gerade den Virtualisierungsmarkt auf und verändert die Softwareentwicklung nachhaltig. Docker verspricht einen schnellen Start, flexible Konfiguration und stabile Images für Entwicklung und Produktion. Wir Entwickler lieben Docker, deployen dort leichtgewichtige Microservices und erstellen System aus vorgefertigten Komponenten des Ökosystems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schön und gut, aber Entwickler und Administratoren müssen die reale Nutzung des Systems kontrollieren. Dies ist eine komplexe Aufgabe die unsere ganze Aufmerksamkeit fordert. In diesem Lab lernst Du, Prometheus einzurichten, um Deine Metriken aus verschiedenen Systeme und Services zu holen. Prometheus verwendet eine Time Series Database (TSDB) mit einer leistungsstarken Abfragesprache mit integrierten komplexen mathematischen Funktionen. Mit Grafana kannst Du eigene Dashboards erstellen, um Deine Metriken zu visualisieren. Alerts können sowohl über herkömmliche Kanäle wie E-Mails oder mit Chat-Systemen, wie Slack integriert werden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prometheus wurde ursprünglich innerhalb von SoundCloud in Berlin entwickelt und wird nun unter dem Dach der Cloud Native Computing Foundation, einer Unterprojekt der Linux Foundation, weiterentwickelt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In diesem Lab lernen die Teilnehmer die Grundkonzepte von Prometheus und Grafana, ihrer Architektur, und wie sie mit Docker betrieben werden. Die Teilnehmer lernen auch, wie man Dashboards baut und Alerts einrichtet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tag-eins-br-docker-monitoring-grundlagen&#34;&gt;Tag Eins: &lt;br&gt;Docker Monitoring Grundlagen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Erstelle einen einfachen Java-basierten Microservice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Überblick über Prometheus und Grafana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Überwache Deine Docker-basierten Microservice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;details-prometheus&#34;&gt;DETAILS PROMETHEUS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prometheus im Detail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Konfiguration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arten von Sensoren&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hinzufügen von Sensoren zu Deinem Code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Erstelle Deine Metrik-Endpunkte&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arbeite mit PromQL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kennzeichne Deine Metriken richtig&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;details-grafana&#34;&gt;DETAILS GRAFANA&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grafana im Detail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Konfiguration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dashboards einrichten&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arbeit mit Prometheus und Grafana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tag-zwei-br-anwendungs-und-node-monitoring&#34;&gt;Tag Zwei: &lt;br&gt; ANWENDUNGS- UND NODE-MONITORING&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;microservices&#34;&gt;Microservices&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Einrichten eines kleinen Docker-Clusters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Überwache Deine Microservices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verwende verschiedene Exporteure

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maschinen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Container&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verwende mehrere Scraper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lerne die richtigen Metriken anzuwenden&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;einrichten-komplexerer-beispiele&#34;&gt;EINRICHTEN KOMPLEXERER BEISPIELE&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Erstelle komplexe Dashboards mit Grafana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verwende Prometheus zur Überwachung von Batch-Jobs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verwende den Prometheus Alert Manager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Schaue in fortgeschrittenere Beispiele&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tipps-und-tricks&#34;&gt;TIPPS UND TRICKS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In die Produktion mit Prometheus und Grafana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vernetze Deine Prometheus-Dienste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aktualisiere Deine Monitoring-Systeme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backup/Restore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;voraussetzungen-und-leistungen&#34;&gt;Voraussetzungen und Leistungen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;zielgruppe-wer-sollte-teilnehmen&#34;&gt;Zielgruppe/ Wer sollte teilnehmen?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DevOps Entwickler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Administratoren&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software- und Systemarchitekten&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;voraussetzungen-an-die-teilnehmer&#34;&gt;Voraussetzungen an die Teilnehmer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grundkenntnisse Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grundkenntnisse Linux (Debian, bash, vim, curl, network, Virtualisierung)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grundkenntnisse Java&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grundkenntnisse Microservices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;leistungen&#34;&gt;Leistungen&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verpflegung: Frühstück, Mittagessen und Getränke (nicht alkoholisch)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Schulungsmaterialien&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nicht enthalten: Hotel Übernachtungen, Anreise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rechner werden nicht gestellt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34; class=&#34;more page open-form&#34; data-form=&#34;docker-camp&#34;&gt;Book now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms of conditions</title>
      <link>https://bee42.com/terms-and-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bee42.com/terms-and-conditions/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;terms-of-conditions&#34;&gt;Terms of conditions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By signing up for a bee42 solutions GmbH training and workshop, the following terms and conditions will be agreed upon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please read these conditions carefully!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;scope-of-application&#34;&gt;Scope of application&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The organizer of the trainings and workshops is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bee42 solutions GmbH,
Am Josephsschacht 72
D-44879 Bochum,
Germany (further on in this document: bee42).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the participation in a bee42 training, the following &amp;ldquo;general conditions for bee42 trainings and workshops&amp;rdquo; apply,
which govern the contractual basis between bee42 and a participant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The valid version of these conditions applies at the time of registration.
The German version shall have priority in the event of an objection or other deviations as well as in disputes over the interpretation of this contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bee42 does not accept any formulations which differ from the &amp;ldquo;General Conditions for bee42 Trainings and Workshops&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bee42 trainings and bee42 workshops are aimed at entrepreneurs.
In the event that a consumer signs up for a bee42 training and bee42 workshop according to the consumer protection law,
the following right of revocation applies to consumers according to the consumer protection law in addition to the &amp;ldquo;General conditions for bee42 training and workshops&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;right-of-withdrawal-for-consumers-according-to-consumer-protection-law&#34;&gt;Right of withdrawal for consumers according to consumer protection law&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a consumer under the Consumer Protection Act, you have the following right of withdrawal in addition to the &amp;ldquo;General Conditions for bee42 Trainings and Workshops&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;right-of-withdrawal-instruction&#34;&gt;Right of withdrawal instruction&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;a.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Right of withdrawal &lt;br/&gt; You may revoke your declaration of the contract in writing (eg letter or e-mail) within 30 days after receipt of a confirmation of registration by bee42 without giving reasons. The punctual sending of the revocation is sufficient for the revocation period.
  The revocation must be sent to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bee42 solutions GmbH
  At the Josephsschacht
  44879 Bochum, Germany&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;E-mail: info@bee42.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;b.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Withdrawal sequence &lt;br/&gt; In the case of an effective revocation, the services received at both ends must be returned and any benefits (eg interest) drawn.
  If you are unable to return the received performance in whole or in part or in a deteriorated condition, you may have to provide us with a decree.
  This may mean that you must nevertheless fulfill the contractual payment obligations for the period up to the cancellation.
  Obligations to reimburse payments must be fulfilled within 30 days.
  The period begins for you with the sending of your declaration of revocation, for us with their receipt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Special instructions &lt;br/&gt; Your right of revocation expires prematurely if the contract is completely fulfilled by both parties at your express request before you have exercised your right of revocation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;End of right of withdrawal instruction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;prices&#34;&gt;Prices&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless otherwise specified in detail, a price quote for a bee42 training or a bee42 workshop is provided as a net price.
If a participant is entitled to deduct the value added tax, he / she is entitled to use the value added tax in Germany to determine the amounts shown on the invoices issued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;participation-requirements&#34;&gt;Participation requirements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The contractual relationship between bee42 and the participant corresponds to the nature of a consulting contract, a service contract.
No promises are made and there are no guarantees or goals to be achieved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The participation requirements stated in the respective training or workshop descriptions are binding and must be adhered to in any case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;booking-cancellation-or-cancellation&#34;&gt;Booking, cancellation or cancellation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;a.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br/&gt; Registration for a bee42-training or a bee42 workshop can be made by e-mail or via the internet form. After receipt of an application, this is confirmed by bee42 in writing. A participant will receive his invoice within 10 days of his registration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;b.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br/&gt; A participant can revoke his registration before the beginning of a bee42 event. In the case of cancellation or cancellation of the registration no additional fees will be levied, if cancellation or cancellation takes place no later than 14 days after the invoice date indicated on the invoice. In the case of cancellation or cancellation of the registration after the said 14 days, the participant must pay 50% of the gross price if cancellation or cancellation takes place no later than 30 days before the start of the event. In the case of a later cancellation or in the event of non-attendance, the participant will be charged the full gross price for participation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br/&gt; The cancellation is subject to the text form. Proof of sending the cancellation is the responsibility of the vendor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;due-date-and-payment&#34;&gt;Due date and payment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless otherwise stated, payment of the invoice amount must be made without deduction 14 days before the start of the event on the bee42 account. Only a full and timely invoice is entitled to attend training or workshop.
The participant will receive an invoice with VAT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;training-place&#34;&gt;Training place&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The place and the times for bee42-trainings and bee42-workshops are given in the respective description.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;scope-of-services&#34;&gt;Scope of Services&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scope of the offer for a bee42 training or workshop includes the participation in the training as well as the dishes and drinks described in the respective description. The price does not include the accommodation costs as well as travel and departure costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;training-deviations&#34;&gt;Training deviations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bee42 reserves the right to make changes to content, in order to always be able to offer up-to-date content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;change-of-venue&#34;&gt;Change of venue&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bee42 reserves the right to change the place of the event due to the number of participants or other important reasons. The distance between the original and the new venue is not more than 20 km.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;cancellation-of-a-bee42-event&#34;&gt;Cancellation of a bee42 event&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bee42 reserves the right to cancel a training or workshop.
Fees paid by the participant before the cancellation will be refunded in full.
For further expenses or other disadvantages, which arise to the participant by the cancellation, bee42 does not come up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;copyright&#34;&gt;Copyright&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All rights, including those of the translation, reprinting and duplication of the training or workshop documents or parts thereof, remain reserved to bee42.
No part of this publication may be reproduced, stored in a retrieval system, or transmitted in any form or by any means, electronic or mechanical, including, An exception to this are the source codes of the sample applications developed in the trainings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;liability-and-warranty&#34;&gt;Liability and warranty&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All trainings and workshops are prepared and carried out by bee42 with the greatest possible care.
Liability for the training or workshop success as well as a liability which is not based on intent or gross negligence are excluded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any personal use of the information provided is solely the responsibility of a participant. For any changes in the personal life or environment of the participant, bee42 assumes no liability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-protection&#34;&gt;Data protection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The careful and conscientious handling of the personal information and data of the participant is important to us.
That is why we do not pass on data to uninvolved third parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each participant agrees with the electronic processing of his personal data by bee42, as far as is necessary for the proper training and workshop management and implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;applicable-law-and-final-provisions&#34;&gt;Applicable law and final provisions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The law of the Federal Republic of Germany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The provisions of the UN purchase or contract law shall not apply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The court of jurisdiction for all disputes arising from this contract is Bochum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should individual provisions of these &amp;ldquo;General Terms and Conditions for bee42 training and workshops&amp;rdquo; be or become invalid in whole or in part, this shall not affect the validity of the remaining provisions. The wholly or partly ineffective regulation is to be replaced by a regulation whose economic success comes as close as possible to the ineffective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Status&lt;/strong&gt;: 19 December 2016&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank you for your booking - bee42</title>
      <link>https://bee42.com/thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bee42.com/thanks/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;thanks-for-your-reservation&#34;&gt;Thanks for your reservation.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;we-ll-inform-you-immediately&#34;&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll inform you immediately.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a  class=&#34;more page&#34; href=&#34;https://bee42.com/index.html&#34;&gt;back to home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker DevOps Camp</title>
      <link>https://bee42.com/trainings/docker-devops-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 20:28:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bee42.com/trainings/docker-devops-camp/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please click here for an &lt;a href=&#34;https://bee42.com/trainings/docker-devops-camp-de&#34;&gt;german version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether small startups or large companies - many companies rely on the open-source Docker technology. But what about the kind of containers that roll up the virtualization market and change the software development in the long term? Docker promises a quick start, flexible configuration and stable images for development and production. In this Docker Camp we want to pursue this promise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We start with an overview and introduce the first steps with the use of Docker. You will get to know the most important commands, instructions and concepts. Using a detailed example, you will learn how to implement a microservice, install with Docker, and integrate with other services in an environment. We also discuss the current Docker ecosystem and clarify opportunities and risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This camp provides you with the Docker basics in comprehensible steps and puts you in the position subsequently to decide whether and how Docker is useful in your business and IT context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-one-br-docker-basics&#34;&gt;Day one: &lt;br&gt;Docker basics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker Basics and Installation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Container Technology Basics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kernel- vs Classical- Virtualization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Architecture of Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Cases and more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup your docker environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Images, Container and Registry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;simple-usage&#34;&gt;Simple Usage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s container run, stop, maintain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker CLI command overview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build your own Images with Dockerfiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build, ship and run Cycle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker Tooling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Volume Management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network Management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logging and Metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backup/Restore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Container Types&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-two-br-create-microservices-with-docker&#34;&gt;Day two: &lt;br&gt; Create microservices with Docker&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;microservices&#34;&gt;Microservices&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think infrastructure first&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a simple Spring Boot App&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build your Toolchain: Java and Maven&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker for Java Developers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create Database Container&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Empower your Development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;infrastructure&#34;&gt;Infrastructure&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build your own Microservice infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a simple build pipeline&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Service Discovery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create Multi Host Networks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn more Docker Tricks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-three-br-scale-your-service-with-docker-swarming&#34;&gt;Day three: &lt;br&gt; Scale your service with Docker Swarming&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;swarming&#34;&gt;Swarming&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scale your services with docker swarming mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update, Failure detection and redeployment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mesh Network and Service Discovery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup a ingress loadbalancer (traefik, haproxy, nginx)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup logging and monitoring systems

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ELK-Stack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prometheus and Grafana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debug your Container&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;go-to-production&#34;&gt;Go to production&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker for production&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build high-quality images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker Security Basics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plugins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Usage tricks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review Best Practices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker on ARM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirements-and-services&#34;&gt;Requirements and Services&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;who-should-participate&#34;&gt;Who should participate&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DevOps developer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Administrators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software and system architects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;required-knowledge&#34;&gt;Required knowledge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic knowledge Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic knowledge Linux (Debian, bash, vim, curl, network, virtualization)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic knowledge of Java&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic knowledge Microservices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;services&#34;&gt;services&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Catering: breakfast, lunch and drinks (non-alcoholic)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Training materials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not included: hotel accommodation, travel expenses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computers are not provided&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>docker for java lab</title>
      <link>https://bee42.com/trainings/docker-for-java-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 22:27:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bee42.com/trainings/docker-for-java-lab/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please click here for an &lt;a href=&#34;https://bee42.com/trainings/docker-for-java-lab-de&#34;&gt;german version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Docker and the exciting ecosystem is very helpful for any Java developer. This lab gives an overview of the best practices to develop Java application with Docker. The Docker ecosystem offers you promising tools for package your software, reuse existing services, database or tools. Docker helps to drive your Continuous Integration Pipeline forward. But, build a good Java Image and setup your container right in production is a challenge. Bundle your Java software and testing your services with Docker can be empower your development. This lab give you some useful hints and discuss tricks to use Docker seamless with Java.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participants&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Java Developer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;System Architects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pre-Knowledge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good Java, Maven and Spring Boot knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker basics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux basics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-one-br-build-your-java-microservice-with-docker&#34;&gt;Day One: &lt;br&gt;Build your Java Microservice with Docker&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker Introduction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Empower your Development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build a Spring Boot Microservices with Maven&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bundle your application with Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create Database Container&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TDD with Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build your own Java Images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debugging your Java at container&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker IDE Support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-two-br-running-java-in-production&#34;&gt;Day Two: &lt;br&gt;Running Java in production&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think infrastructure first&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic Image Build with a Cloud/CI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build your Toolchain: Java, Maven, Tomcat, &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create optimal Java tooling with Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12 Factor Rules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scale your Java Microservices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Running Java Micorservices in production&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add metrics and logging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker GitLab/CI Lab</title>
      <link>https://bee42.com/trainings/docker-gitlab-ci-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 22:16:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bee42.com/trainings/docker-gitlab-ci-lab/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please click here for an &lt;a href=&#34;https://bee42.com/trainings/docker-gilab-ci-lab-de&#34;&gt;german version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether small startups or large companies - many companies rely on the open-source Docker technology. But what about the kind of containers that roll up the virtualization market and change the software development in the long term? Docker promises a quick start, flexible configuration and stable images for development and production. Nice, but a developer or operator must be setup there automation to build, test and deliver Docker images. At this training you learn to setup GitLab/CI to maintain your project sources and automate your Continuous Integration and Delivery pipeline for Docker images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We start with an overview and introduce the first steps with the use of GitLab/CI. You will get to know the most important components, instructions and concepts. Using a detailed example, you will learn how to implement a microservice, automate the build with different gitlab runner, install with Docker, test and integrate with other services in an environment. We also discuss to deliver your image to your environment. Also we want to discuss how you can trigger your builds, make good Docker images and ship images to your Docker registry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-one-br-gitlab-ci-basics&#34;&gt;Day one: &lt;br&gt;GitLab/CI basics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is GitLab and what it is not ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installation of GitLab Instance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview of the GitLab Architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detailed overview about the GitLab components&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup the various GitLab components&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitLab UI overview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check in a simple project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;workflow-with-your-images-from-gitlab&#34;&gt;Workflow with your Images from GitLab&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s build and test Docker images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Push your successfully built images to registry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build your own images with Dockerfiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create your own GitLab Runners of different types

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker machine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSH&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;listen-to-your-gitlab-infrastructure&#34;&gt;Listen to your GitLab Infrastructure&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logging and Monitoring for your GitLab Infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backup and Restore your Images from GitLab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-two-br-ship-a-tested-microservice-with-docker-and-gitlab&#34;&gt;Day two: &lt;br&gt; Ship a tested microservice with Docker and GitLab&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;microservices&#34;&gt;Microservices&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a simple Spring Boot Application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build your Toolchain for Application Development (Java and Maven)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Empower your Application Development with Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distribute your Microservice in a &lt;strong&gt;neat Dockerfile&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship your Microservice to a production like System with Delivery Concept&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gitlab-ci-tipps-and-tricks&#34;&gt;GitLab/CI Tipps and Tricks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain your GitLab with a few steps for

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updating your Installation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backup and Restore your Installation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scale your CI CD Pipeline with different concepts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites-and-services&#34;&gt;Prerequisites and Services&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;who-should-participate&#34;&gt;Who should participate&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DevOps developer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Administrators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software and system architects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;required-knowledge&#34;&gt;Required knowledge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic knowledge Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic knowledge Linux (Debian, bash, vim, curl, network, virtualization)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic knowledge of Java, Maven and SpringBoot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic knowledge Microservices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;services&#34;&gt;services&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Catering: breakfast, lunch and drinks (non-alcoholic)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Training materials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not included: hotel accommodation, travel expenses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computers are not provided&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Prometheus Lab</title>
      <link>https://bee42.com/trainings/docker-prometheus-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 22:27:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bee42.com/trainings/docker-prometheus-lab/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please click here for an &lt;a href=&#34;https://bee42.com/trainings/docker-prometheus-lab-de&#34;&gt;german version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether small startups or large companies - many companies rely on the open-source Docker technology. But what about the kind of containers that roll up the virtualization market and change the software development in the long term? Docker promises a quick start, flexible configuration and stable images for development and production. We developers love Docker and deploy the microservices on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nice, but developer and operator must be control the real usage of the system. This is a complex, but useful task at your daily work. At this training you learn to set up Prometheus to grab your metrics from system and services. Prometheus uses a time series database featuring a powerful query language with integrated complex mathematical functions. With Grafana your can create your own dashboards to visualize your metrics. Alerts can be sent both via traditional channels such as email, or integrated with chat systems such as Slack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prometheus was originally developed by SoundCloud and is now under the umbrella of the Cloud Native Computing Foundation, which is a sub-project of the Linux Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this training, participants will learn the basic concepts of Prometheus and Grafana, its architecture, how it can be deployed with Docker. Participants will also learn how to build dashboards and set up alerts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-one-br-docker-service-monitoring-basics&#34;&gt;Day one: &lt;br&gt;Docker Service Monitoring basics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a simple Java-based microservice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview of Prometheus and Grafana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitor your Docker-based microservice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;details-prometheus&#34;&gt;Details Prometheus&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How it works&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Types of sensors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add sensors to your code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create metrics endpoints&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work with PromQL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Label your metrics right&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;details-grafana&#34;&gt;Details Grafana&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How it works&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up Dashboards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work with Prometheus and Grafana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-two-br-application-and-node-monitoring&#34;&gt;Day two: &lt;br&gt; Application and Node Monitoring&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;microservices&#34;&gt;Microservices&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup a small Docker cluster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitor your microservices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use different exporters

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Containers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use multiple scrapers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to use the right metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;setup-more-complex-examples&#34;&gt;Setup more complex examples&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup complex dashboards with Grafana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Prometheus for monitoring batch jobs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the Prometheus Alertmanager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look into more advanced examples&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tips-and-tricks&#34;&gt;Tips and Tricks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to productions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Federate your Prometheus services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgrade your monitoring systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backup/Restore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites-and-services&#34;&gt;Prerequisites and Services&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;who-should-participate&#34;&gt;Who should participate&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DevOps developer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Administrators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software and system architects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;required-knowledge&#34;&gt;Required knowledge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic knowledge Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic knowledge Linux (Debian, bash, vim, curl, network, virtualization)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic knowledge of Java&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic knowledge Microservices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;services&#34;&gt;services&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Catering: breakfast, lunch and drinks (non-alcoholic)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Training materials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not included: hotel accommodation, travel expenses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computers are not provided&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>