<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog-rsses on bee42 solutions gmbh</title>
    <link>https://bee42.com/blog/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog-rsses on bee42 solutions gmbh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bee42.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Impressions from CloudNativeCon and KubeCon Europe 2017, Berlin</title>
      <link>https://bee42.com/blog/kubecon-europe-2017-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bee42.com/blog/kubecon-europe-2017-berlin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We visited the &lt;a href=&#34;http://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/cloudnativecon-and-kubecon-europe&#34;&gt;CloudNativeCon and KubeCon Europe 2017&lt;/a&gt; in Berlin at the end of March. This two-day conference was equipped with highly-skilled speakers which gave the audience a great insight in todays and future container technologies from Docker and Kubernetes, and other a lot of other firms in the Cloud Native ecosystem as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The announcement which impressed us most was, that Docker Inc. did contributed their Open Source industry-standard container runtime &amp;ldquo;containerd&amp;rdquo; project into the hands of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cncf.io&#34;&gt;Cloud Native Computing Foundation CNCF&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/kubecon-europe-2017-berlin/kubecon-containerd.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;KubeCon&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://containerd.io&#34;&gt;containerd&lt;/a&gt; is basically the heart of the Docker project and therefor the main runtime to execute Docker containers on a broad range of operating systems from different Linux distros and it even works Windows. This is really a great step into a fully open containerized future where the container runtime itself is now under the control of the CNCF and not only developed by a single company. BTW, at the same time the alternative container engine &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rkt/rkt&#34;&gt;rkt&lt;/a&gt; from CoreOS has been also contributed to and is accepted by the CNCF - so, the users do have a real choice between two different container runtimes directly supported and maintained by the CNCF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another highlight of the KubeCon Europe 2017 was the talk by 17 year-old Lucas Käldström who is the youngest Kubernetes maintainer. He did a similar talk two weeks before at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io&#34;&gt;DevOps Gathering 2017&lt;/a&gt; conference in Bochum, here you&amp;rsquo;ll find the recorded talk &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MxeVwAbRbDM&amp;amp;index=4&amp;amp;list=PLfE26KO4gJKAkrcxjCxoapWmljYKF9qTr&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Intel and ARM, let Kubernetes rule them all!&amp;rdquo;, by Lucas Käldström&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below you&amp;rsquo;ll find some impressions taken at the cool venue of the Berlin Conference Center &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bcc-berlin.de/en&#34;&gt;bcc&lt;/a&gt; in the middle of Berlin, Germany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/kubecon-europe-2017-berlin/kubecon-cncf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;KubeCon&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/kubecon-europe-2017-berlin/kubecon-aparna-sinha.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;KubeCon&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/kubecon-europe-2017-berlin/kubecon-alexis-richardson.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;KubeCon&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/kubecon-europe-2017-berlin/kubecon-chen-goldberg.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;KubeCon&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/kubecon-europe-2017-berlin/kubecon-joe-beda.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;KubeCon&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/kubecon-europe-2017-berlin/kubecon-kelsey-hightower.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;KubeCon&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bee42 Crew&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevOps Gathering 2017 - Container Open Space</title>
      <link>https://bee42.com/blog/DevOps-Gathering-Open-Space/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bee42.com/blog/DevOps-Gathering-Open-Space/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bee42.com/blog/DevOps-Gathering-Conference-Day/&#34;&gt;previous blog post&lt;/a&gt; we took you with us to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bee42.com/blog/devops-gathering-workshops/&#34;&gt;workshop day&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://bee42.com/blog/DevOps-Gathering-Conference-Day/&#34;&gt;conference day&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;a href=&#34;devops-gathering.io&#34;&gt;DevOps Gathering&lt;/a&gt; last week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blogpost you’ll get to know all about the third and last day of the conference DevOps Gathering: The Container Open Space!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what is an Open Space and what had the attendees to bring with them to take part in this Open Space? The answer is: Only them, good ideas and curiosity! And before we will tell you what happened on Saturday, we’d like to introduce you first to the format of an Open Space:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-space-what-is-that&#34;&gt;Open Space - What is that?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An Open Space is a simple and productive way for hosting knowledge events. Participants and experts create and manage together their own agenda of parallel working sessions. The goal of this Open Space is to allow attendees to interact with one another and learn from each other – all under the guidance of an experienced moderator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here you can find some links, definitions and videos we’ve collected for you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Definition of Open Space Technology (Wikipedia): &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_Space_Technology&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_Space_Technology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Space concept explained (in English): &lt;a href=&#34;http://openspaceworld.org/wp2/explore/open-space-key-concepts/&#34;&gt;http://openspaceworld.org/wp2/explore/open-space-key-concepts/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video and explanation of Open Space (in German): &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eZD0PtnN1vQ&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eZD0PtnN1vQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video and explanation of Open Space (in English): &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M_jhcvCYBbg&amp;amp;t=1s&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M_jhcvCYBbg&amp;amp;t=1s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;open-space-what-will-happen&#34;&gt;Open Space - What will happen&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We never know exactly what will happen when we open the space for people to do their most important work, but we can guarantee these results when any group gets into Open Space:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All of the issues that are MOST important to the participants will be raised.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All of the issues raised will be addressed by those participants most qualified and capable of getting something done on each of them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a time as short as one day, all of the most important ideas, discussion, recommendations, conclusions, questions for further study, and plans for immediate action will be documented in each session.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the end, all results of each session will available and briefly discussed with all participants of the day.
AND… results like these can be planned and implemented faster than any other kind of so-called “large-group intervention.” It is literally possible to accomplish in one day what some other approaches take weeks or months to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;to-lead-an-openspace-talk&#34;&gt;To lead an OpenSpace Talk&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Come up with an interesting topic and title for your discussion. You don’t need to develop these before the conference; most of the ideas will come to you during the event, but be prepared this is also an option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fill out a schedule Post-It for your topic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Place the topic on the schedule.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you see topics that have something in common, consider combining them into a single time slot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a significant number of people want to attend your discussion and another discussion in the same time slot, try to trade into another time slot to ensure maximum dialogue and participation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To attend an OpenSpace Talk:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check the schedule and sign up for a talk or just drop in if you wish. Use the ‘Law of two feet.’ If you feel that you are not contributing or benefiting from a presentation, please feel free to move on to something else. Allow the discussion convener to steer his or her topic. If you have an opposing opinion that needs a full time slot you should feel free to add your own OpenSpace slot to discuss the topic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_open_space/poster-open-space-rules.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Open Space Poster&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Many Thanks to Yuliana&lt;/strong&gt;
(y.stepanova@setlog.com)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rules of an Open Space&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whoever shows up is the right people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whatever happens is the only thing that could have&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whenever it starts is the right time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When it’s over, it’s over&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;devops-gathering-2017-container-open-space-on-march-25-2017&#34;&gt;DevOps Gathering 2017 - Container Open Space on March 25, 2017&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DevOps Gathering Open Space format was a perfect fit to the fast moving development of the container ecosystem. It offered participants and experts the opportunity to launch discussions, address questions and challenges regarding Docker, Kubernetes and Cloud technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The topic of our Open Space was: What technical challenges emerge with Docker and Kubernetes?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among others, we addressed the following questions:
* Do we know and proper use the benefits of existing solutions?
* What experience do we already have with Docker or Kubernetes in production?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;and-here-we-like-to-show-you-some-selected-topics-and-session-the-participants-and-groups-discussed-and-interchange-about&#34;&gt;And here we like to show you some selected topics and session the participants and groups discussed and interchange about:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configuration &amp;amp; Deployment hell (and how to avoid it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dev Sec Ops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monkey &amp;amp; Bananas in DevOps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software is eating the world (Impact &amp;amp; Ethics)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to integrate DevOps into Scrum team?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bringing Docker to your beginners team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating Kubernetes Clusters easily and running cool stuff on top&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Containerizing Legacy Applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CI and Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PromQL basis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore we had a &lt;strong&gt;hacker room&lt;/strong&gt; for practitioners among the participants and there our experts Peter Roßbach, Dieter Reuter, Niclas Mietz and Lucas Käldström guided our attendees through some practical stuff:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up a big ARM cluster up &amp;amp; running&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30 Raspberry PI 3 (w/ 32bit and 64bit HypriotOS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Up Boards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ODROID-C2 Boards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C.H.I.P. and Pi Zero Boards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Connect a Kubernetes and Docker Swarm in one big cluster&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use Traefik as external ingress loadbalancer&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Automated integration test with Spring Boot and a dockerized database&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some hours we had setup the basic ARM containers (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bee42/docker-on-rpi-lab&#34;&gt;https://github.com/bee42/docker-on-rpi-lab&lt;/a&gt;), flashed and connected all machines at the network. Cool, but we can’t find a simple solution to connect the Docker swarming network with the Kubernetes flannel one. We need more hacktime to fix that :-) We’ve learned a lot of mixing container ARM cluster setups and migrate them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-space-lighting-talks&#34;&gt;Open Space - Lighting Talks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the Open Space we gave the participants the chance for lightning talks.
At every event a lot of attendees have idea for some other talks or topics they like to introduce to the other participants. So we gave them the chance to bring their most interested topic to the audience. The participants had 10 minutes to talk about their tool, project or experience with container and DevOps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the lightning talks we had on last saturday:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Radical Agility” by Jan Stroppel (Zalando)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Mokikz” - a project by Wolfgang Lang (SEAL Systems), where he make technology and programming accessible for the kidz (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Mokikz/ldu&#34;&gt;https://github.com/Mokikz/ldu&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Acceptance Testing using Selenium and Docker” by Kevin Wittek (G Data)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;impressions-and-pictures-of-the-devops-gathering-open-space&#34;&gt;Impressions and pictures of the DevOps Gathering Open Space&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_open_space/empty-open-space-agenda.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Open Space empty agenda&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_open_space/open-space-moderator.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Open Space introduction&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_open_space/introduction-open-space.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Open Space introduction&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_open_space/open-space-first-steps.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Open Space introduction&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_open_space/interaction-open-space.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Open Space introduction&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_open_space/open-space-first-interaction.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Open Space introduction&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_open_space/topics-introduction-open-space.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Open Space introduction&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_open_space/filled-agenda-open-space.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Open Space introduction&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_open_space/happy-open-space.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Open Space introduction&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_open_space/open-space-session-another-outside.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Open Space introduction&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_open_space/lightning-talk-open-space.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Open Space introduction&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_open_space/group-discussion-no2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Open Space introduction&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_open_space/group-picture-open-space.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Open Space introduction&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevOps Gathering 2017 - Docker on Windows Workshop</title>
      <link>https://bee42.com/blog/DevOps-Gathering-Docker-on-Windows-Workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bee42.com/blog/DevOps-Gathering-Docker-on-Windows-Workshop/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-started-with-docker-on-windows-server-2016&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Getting started with Docker on Windows Server 2016&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;by-a-href-https-twitter-com-stefscherer-stefan-scherer-a-and-a-href-https-twitter-com-quintus23m-dieter-reuter-a-both-docker-captains&#34;&gt;by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/stefscherer&#34;&gt;Stefan Scherer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Quintus23M&#34;&gt;Dieter Reuter&lt;/a&gt; (both Docker Captains)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/&#34;&gt;DevOps Gathering&lt;/a&gt; - a conference about DevOps, Docker, Kubernetes, Microservices and so on - I prepared a &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/workshops/Getting-started-with-Docker-on-Windows-Server-2016/&#34;&gt;workshop&lt;/a&gt; to get started with Docker on Windows Server 2016. More and more people are attracted by the new way to deploy and run services with Docker and native Windows containers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this three hour hands-on workshop the attendees had the chance to get a deep understanding what containers are, how to build an Docker images, where to find images on the Docker Hub, how to write good Dockerfiles for Windows and how to persist data using volumes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was my first workshop of this kind and so I hoped that WiFi works well for the workshop. I provided plenty Windows Server 2016 machines in Microsoft Azure Cloud and the attendees used RDP to connect to these machines. With this setup nobody had to setup local VM&amp;rsquo;s and it was easy to run the workshop. Even working from a tablet worked quite well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr-docker-windows-workshop/docker-on-windows-workshop-stefan-scherer-dieter-reuter.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Docker Captains Stefan Scherer and Dieter Reuter&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even Docker experts on Linux learned some small tricks that apply for both the Linux and Windows platform. They also were astonished how good the Docker support on Windows has evolved. Most of the features that you will use in a Dockerfile or a docker-compose.yml are also implemented on Windows. So deploying and running containers look pretty much the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr-docker-windows-workshop/docker-on-windows-workshop-teilnehmer.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering attendees at the docker on windows workshop&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all the attendees for the feedback and that you liked the workshop. Some of you even have ideas for some next projects with Docker on Windows. The the most wanted features are running Docker in Docker to setup Windows CI servers and having full overlay network support in Docker Swarm mode. Let&amp;rsquo;s see what Microsoft and Docker come up with in the next few months&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/stefscherer&#34;&gt;Stefan Scherer&lt;/a&gt;, Docker Captain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr-docker-windows-workshop/happy-teilnehmer-docker-on-windows-devops-gathering.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering attendees happy at the docker on windows workshop&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr-docker-windows-workshop/docker-on-windows-slides-dieter-reuter-stefan-scherer-docker-captains.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Docker Captains Dieter Reuter and Stefan Scherer Docker on Windows Workshop&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevOps Gathering 2017 - Conference Day on March 24</title>
      <link>https://bee42.com/blog/DevOps-Gathering-Conference-Day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bee42.com/blog/DevOps-Gathering-Conference-Day/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We had a long journey and put a lot of effort and time into the project DevOps Gathering - And on the 24th March 2017, when the Conference Days finally started, everything payed off!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may read in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bee42.com/blog/devops-gathering-workshops/&#34;&gt;previous blogpost&lt;/a&gt;, we had some pre-conference workshops to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io&#34;&gt;DevOps Gathering&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday the 23rd March. They took place in the the campus of the Ruhr University in Bochum (RUB).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sponsors&#34;&gt;SPONSORS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the main conference day on Friday and Saturday we organized a special location in the ruhr area: The G Data Campus, a location with a over a 100 years of history (If you like to read the full history about this location - you can find it &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gdata.de/news/g-data-grundstein-fuer-expansion-in-bochum-gelegt&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, unfortunately only in German) . &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gdata.de/&#34;&gt;G Data Software company&lt;/a&gt;, a german IT security pioneer, was our this year location and conference party sponsor. At this point - once again a BIG THANK YOU to G Data for being our supportive sponsor!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course - We don’t want to miss all the other sponsors of the DevOps Gathering 2017:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;as already mentioned - &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/#gdata&#34;&gt;G DATA&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bee42.com&#34;&gt;bee42&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/#setlog&#34;&gt;Setlog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/#wifo&#34;&gt;Bochum Wirtschaftsentwicklung&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/#openknowledge&#34;&gt;open knowledge&lt;/a&gt; as a t-shirt sponsor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/#host1plus&#34;&gt;Host1Plus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/#codecentric&#34;&gt;codecentric&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/#9elements&#34;&gt;9elements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/#aufgeweckt&#34;&gt;agentur aufgeweckt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/#dpunkt&#34;&gt;dpunkt verlag&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/#styracosoft&#34;&gt;styracosoft&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find all information about our sponsors on out conference website: &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/&#34;&gt;https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-program-talks-and-speakers&#34;&gt;THE PROGRAM, TALKS AND SPEAKERS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One evening before the conference days, on Thursday after the workshops day, we prepared the location at the G Data Campus and organized the last stuff and prepared everything, what we had to do: The Check-In Desk, the Sponsors Area, the Conference Room and so on. We were so excited about the first official conference day! :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the morning of the first main conference day the organizer &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/PRossbach&#34;&gt;Peter Roßbach&lt;/a&gt; warmly welcomed all attendees, sponsors and speakers with some key facts about the Conference and of course with information about the upcoming IT Revolution, about Docker, about organisation transformation and technology shift, and all the other topics that we entered in our program and talks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We assembled such a great &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/#speakers&#34;&gt;speaker line up&lt;/a&gt; and welcomed so many Docker Captains (three), international and national experts on the first day of the DevOps Gathering - As you can see in our following &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/#talks&#34;&gt;schedule (March 24th)&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“How we run Kubernetes in Kubernetes, aka Kubeception” &lt;strong&gt;by Timo Derstappen (Giant Swarm)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Docker Container Loading” &lt;strong&gt;by Roland Huss (RedHat)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Docker Orchestration and Swarming” &lt;strong&gt;by Peter Roßbach (bee42 solutions)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“One year monitoring a small startup with Prometheus: lessons learned” &lt;strong&gt;by Maykel Moya (ShuttleCloud)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Build and deploy multiarch Linux and Windows Container images” &lt;strong&gt;by Docker Captain Stefan Scherer (SEAL Systems)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Intel and ARM, let Kubernetes rule them all!” &lt;strong&gt;by the talented Lucas Käldström&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Make load-balancing great again with Træfik!” &lt;strong&gt;by Emile Vauge and Manuel Laufenberg (both working for traefik.io)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Getting the most out of your containerized database” &lt;strong&gt;by Claus Matzinger (crate.io)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keynote: “DevOps is not enough – towards a DevOps ecosystem” &lt;strong&gt;by Uwe Friedrichsen (codecentric)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the full schedule including the abstracts, more pictures and the slides of the talks on our website: &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/#talks&#34;&gt;https://devops-gathering.io/#talks&lt;/a&gt;. Just click on the talk you like to see and you will find all further information on the subsite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-recorded-all-sessions-for-you&#34;&gt;We recorded ALL sessions for you&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who think slides are not enough or for those who hadn’t the chance and time to participate in this special community conference, we have some good news for you: All talks of the conference day were recorded! We&amp;rsquo;ll upload all conference talks including the slides within the next weeks via our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCQZcFFlmKBBAhvSupNTm2tw&#34;&gt;DevOps Gathering Youtube Channel&lt;/a&gt;! Besides that we&amp;rsquo;ll put them of course directly on our website &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io&#34;&gt;devops-gathering.io&lt;/a&gt;. You want to be the first to know about the uploaded talks? Then…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;subscribe our youtube channel to see them directly when they’re online: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCQZcFFlmKBBAhvSupNTm2tw&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCQZcFFlmKBBAhvSupNTm2tw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;just subscribe for our bee42 newsletter here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/ghGIxV&#34;&gt;https://goo.gl/ghGIxV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and follow us on twitter via DevOps Gathering and bee42 solutions for the hot news: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/DevOpsGathering&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/DevOpsGathering&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bee42solutions&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/bee42solutions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;d like to read and know what happened at the Open Space on the last day of the Conference DevOps Gathering, then read the next blogpost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;impressions-of-the-devops-gathering-conference-day&#34;&gt;Impressions of the DevOps Gathering Conference Day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt; HEAD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog//dogr_conference/DevOps-Gathering-2017-Conference.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;devops-gathering-conference-attendees-https-bee42-com-images-blog-dogr-conference-devops-gathering-2017-jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/DevOps-Gathering-2017.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference Attendees&#34; /&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog//dogr_conference/DevOps-Gathering-2017-Conference.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/images/blog/dogr_conference/DevOps-Gathering-2017.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference Attendees&#34; /&gt;
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; origin/master&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/claus-matzinger-devops-gathering.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference Claus Matzinger&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/DevOps-Gathering-Peter-Rossbach.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference Peter Roßbach&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/DevOps-Gathering-Introduction.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference Introduction&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/dieter-reuter-lucas-kaeldtroem-devops-gathering.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference Docker Captain and Lucas Käldström&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/Docker-Captain-at-DevOps-Gathering.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference Docker Captain&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/Docker-Captain-and-Lucas-Kaeldstroem-DevOps-Gathering.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference Introduction&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/docker-captain-stefan-scherer-devops-gathering.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference Stefan Scherer&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt; HEAD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;devops-gathering-conference-attendees-https-bee42-com-images-blog-dogr-conference-teilnehmer-devops-gathering-jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/teilnehmer-devops-gathering.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference attendees&#34; /&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;ihttps://bee42.com/mages/blog/dogr_conference/teilnehmer-devops-gathering.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference attendees&#34; /&gt;
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; origin/master&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/lucas-kaeldstroem-devops-gathering-talk.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference Stage&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/peter-rossbach-roland-huss-devops-gathering-stage.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/teilnehmer-frage-devops-gathering.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference participants&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/peter-rossbach-roland-huss-maven-birthday.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference Docker Maven PlugIn&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/teilnehmer-frage-runde-devops-gathering.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference Teilnehmer&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/timo-derstappen-lachen-on-stage.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference Fun&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/teilnehmer-fragerunde-devops-gathering.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference questions&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/traefik-at-DevOps-Gathering-2017.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference traefik&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/traefik-at-devops-gathering.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference traefik&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/Uwe-Friedrichsen-codecentric-DevOps-Gathering.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference &#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevOps Gathering Workshops</title>
      <link>https://bee42.com/blog/devops-gathering-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bee42.com/blog/devops-gathering-workshops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On March 23th we organized some very interesting Docker Workshops as pre-conference workshops to the conference &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/&#34;&gt;DevOps Gathering 2017&lt;/a&gt;! The attendess had the chance to learn from Docker Captains and experts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to set up an automated container building pipeline with GitLab/CI?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to build and deploy multi-arch Linux and Windows Container images?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to operate Java applications with Docker and Kubernetes?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to setup Docker Swarm cluster on AWS?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to develop, test and deploy software in Docker using tools such as Spring-Boot and Gradle?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dealing with new possibilities of software development and deployment with DevOps tools like Docker, Kubernetes and Cloud-Computing was practically addressed at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/#workshops&#34;&gt;DevOps Gathering pre-conference workshops&lt;/a&gt;. The attendees had the chance to learn from DevOps experts from companies like RedHat, styracosoft, AutoScout24, Seal Systems and of course bee42 solutions. We are proud to have nearly all german Docker Captains (three!) hold workshops and shared their deep Docker tips and tricks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the GitLab/CI Workshop, &lt;strong&gt;Niclas Mietz from bee42 solutions&lt;/strong&gt;, showed in the first stage the easy use of GitLab. After this the attendees got an instructed way to build a CI and CD pipeline to deliver her first container on a system. The next stage was to get a deeper knowledge of the architecture and the concepts of the GitLab/CI ecosystem. After finishing these both stages, a new Microservice project got imported and a CI pipeline was built for this Microservice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stefan Scherer&lt;/strong&gt; from Seal Systems and &lt;strong&gt;Dieter Reuter&lt;/strong&gt; from bee42 solutions, &lt;strong&gt;both Docker Captains&lt;/strong&gt;, showed new features of the Windows Servers 2016 and its integration to run Docker and Windows Containers. By pulling Docker images from the Docker Hub and run it on the Docker Engine, attendees learned to configure TCP/IP ports and volumes to connect running container to the outside world.
Successfully taking an application based upon microservices and dockerize it into a set of Windows containers, was the goal of the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roland Huss from RedHat&lt;/strong&gt; showed his attendees how to add two connected Microservices based on Wildly-Swarm and Spring-Boot, Roland demonstrated live the creation of Docker images to Maven builds and how to simplify integration tests by Docker. Running and orchestrating these images on Kubernetes was the second part of the workshop. The integration with the fabric8-maven-plugin was shown in more detail. Finally, the attendees got a good overview how to put several Java applications in containers and how to orchestrate them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Philipp Garbe from AutoScout24&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Docker Captain&lt;/strong&gt;, showed in his workshop how to run Docker Containers on AWS. In his hands-on workshop he started to guide his attendees through the basic setups with all local requirements and the immutable infrastructure with CloudFormation. Further the attendees learned to run Docker on EC2 (VMs) and how to scale with AutoScaling Groups. Finally, with the setup of Docker Swarm clusters on AWS, everyone was able to deploy and update applications based on Docker Compose v3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kevin Wittek and Matthias Rottländer, both from styracosoft&lt;/strong&gt;, took the attendees through the complete development lifecycle of a simple microservice, using familiar tools such as Spring-Boot and Gradle. Based on practical examples the workshop started with running Spring-Boot Apps inside a Docker container and building Spring-Boot Docker images using Gradle. Using containers for unit and integration tests in Spring-Boot Apps with Spock and Docker and deploying and configuring Spring-Boot microservices using docker-compose, gave an insight to new possibilities of up to date development and testing environments&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the full schedule and agenda, all workshops and talks of the DevOps Gathering 2017 on our website &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/&#34;&gt;devops-gathering.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you once again to all our Speakers, Docker Daptains, Experts and of course the Attendees! We are looking forward to the next DevOps Gathering and Workshops!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bee42/DevOps Gathering Crew&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4th Docker Birthday Party in the Ruhr Area</title>
      <link>https://bee42.com/blog/4th-Docker-Birthday/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bee42.com/blog/4th-Docker-Birthday/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/all_cakes_docker.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Cakes Worldwide&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We love to use Docker in our daily business, that&amp;rsquo;s also why we organize a week after the Docker Birthday the &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io&#34;&gt;DevOps Gathering&lt;/a&gt; (March 23 - 25, 2017) in Bochum, a conference for Docker container, Kubernetes, DevOps and more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that was NO excuse not to celebrate the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.docker.com/2017/02/announcing-docker-birthday-4-spreading-docker-love/&#34;&gt;4th Docker Birthday&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/birthday_wal_bee42.png&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Whale bee42&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;first-of-all-a-big-thank-you-to&#34;&gt;First of all..a BIG THANK YOU to&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;strong&gt;Karen Bajza&lt;/strong&gt; for spreading the Docker love and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.docker.com/2017/02/announcing-docker-birthday-4-spreading-docker-love/&#34;&gt;4th birthday vibes&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tech.zalando.com/?gh_src=4n3gxh1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zalando&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for sponsoring this Docker Birthday Party in Dortmund and making this event possible!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.setlog.com/de/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setlog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; also for sponsoring this  birthday meetup!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bee42.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bee42&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for sponsoring the awesome, big (!!!) and delicious Docker Container Cake! (you can have a look below, there are a lot of pictures)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;our gorgeous baker of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.baeckerei-mohr.de/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bakery Mohr&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in Dortmund - thank you for the great cake and the details!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;our mentors &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/PRossbach&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/solidnerd&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Niclas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jans0510&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Albert &amp;amp; Dima&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dimi8795&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dimitry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Kiview&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kevin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  - thank you for your support and expertise!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;Docker Captains &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/marcosnils&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marcos Lilljedahl&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/xetorthio&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jonathan Leibiusky&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for creating play-with-docker, a fun and easy way to work through these labs and courses!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-facts&#34;&gt;KEY FACTS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we tell and report you about OUR 4th Docker Birthday celebration, we&amp;rsquo;d like to give you some key facts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;Docker in 80+ countries!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;over 154 Docker Birthday #4 celebrations were announced for this year!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;over 650 tweets about this year Docker Birthday celebration!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;6000+ RSVPs worldwide!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;700+ Docker mentors worldwide!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;take-aways-of-the-docker-birthday-last-week&#34;&gt;TAKE AWAYS of the Docker Birthday last week:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;slides of this Docker Birthday MeetUp: &lt;a href=&#34;https://speakerdeck.com/rossbachp/docker-birthday-introduction-meetup-bochum-dortmund&#34;&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/rossbachp/docker-birthday-introduction-meetup-bochum-dortmund&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;discount code for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io&#34;&gt;DevOps Gathering&lt;/a&gt; in Bochum, Germany (30% off with the code: &lt;strong&gt;docker30&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;discount code for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://2017.dockercon.com/&#34;&gt;DockerCon&lt;/a&gt; in Austin,TX USA (30% off with the code: &lt;strong&gt;BDAY4&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kevin &amp;amp; Ali from &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/adessoAG&#34;&gt;adesso&lt;/a&gt; won tickets (2-Day-Passes) for the DevOps Gathering!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;our-docker-birthday-party&#34;&gt;OUR DOCKER BIRTHDAY PARTY&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Docker Birthday #4 was celebrated at Zalando on the 16th March 2017. We brought both Community Groups from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/de-DE/Docker-Bochum/&#34;&gt;Bochum&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/de-DE/Docker-Dortmund/&#34;&gt;Dortmund&lt;/a&gt; together to celebrate this event. To celebrate together we warmly welcomed newcomers and the already known Docker friends! We provided free Docker labs and courses to learn about Docker in a fun and inviting way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had hands-on with self-paced tutorials for every experience level from absolute beginners to professionals (with focus on beginners to intermediate).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The agenda for the Docker Birthday Party was as the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;18:00 - 18:30: Come together for dinner (Pizza &amp;amp; Drinks)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;18:30 - 18:45: Salutation and introductory words&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;18:45 - 20:45: Mentoring sessions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20:45 - 22:00: Celebration with drinks and a very special cake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a little schedule to finish all things we want to do. Our Meetup started with Pizza and Drinks to get strong enough for all problems that we wanted to resolve. After this &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/PRossbach&#34;&gt;Peter Rossbach&lt;/a&gt;, our Docker expert, held an short introduction about Docker and the Docker Birthday courses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/Introduction_DockerBirthday_Peter_Rossbach.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Introduction by Peter Rossbach&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With ending of the introduction all participants built small groups to handle the courses in a timeframe of two hours. In some groups there were dedicated Mentors for the courses, because Mentors likes as well to learn new stuff and take challenges :) . And the other groups could get help from Mentors on-demand or Mentors ask them if they can help on the problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/DockerBirthday_Working_in_Groups.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Labs and courses&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After our timeframe ended, we missed some important step: The Docker Birthday Cake - The most important part of the evening!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looked so small but trust us - the cake was 20 centimeters high, 20 kg heavy and it was filled with raspberry (pi, hihi) creme and chocolate!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/Docker_Birthday_Cake_Container.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Cake&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After our stomach hurted from the delicious cake and the little sugar overdose, we took our chance make a selfie with some people:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/Selfie_DockerBirthday_Party.png&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Selfie&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next year we want to repeat this great event. We hope that you can join us as well to celebrate this day! :-)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/DockerBirthday_Webcam_Video.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Celebration&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/docker-birthday-cake-full.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Moby Dock&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/docker-birthday-celebration-sitting-labs-fun.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Docker Labs&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/docker_birthday_party_meetup.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday MeetUp&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/docker-birthday-cake-details-gopher.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Gopher Cake&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/DockerBirthday_fun.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Fun&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/Docker_Whale_Lego_DockerBirthday.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Moby Dock&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/docker-birthday-cake-details-mini-cake.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Gopher Cake&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/docker-birthday-celebration-fun.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Party MeetUp&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/docker-birthday-container-cake-details.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Cake Details&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/Docker-Birthday-Discussion.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Group Discussion&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/docker-birthday-labs-groups.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Group MeetUp&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/docker-birthday-party-cake.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Cake the day after&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>