<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog-rsses on bee42 solutions gmbh</title>
    <link>https://bee42.com/blog/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog-rsses on bee42 solutions gmbh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bee42.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>DevOps Gathering 2017 - Conference Day on March 24</title>
      <link>https://bee42.com/blog/DevOps-Gathering-Conference-Day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bee42.com/blog/DevOps-Gathering-Conference-Day/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We had a long journey and put a lot of effort and time into the project DevOps Gathering - And on the 24th March 2017, when the Conference Days finally started, everything payed off!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may read in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bee42.com/blog/devops-gathering-workshops/&#34;&gt;previous blogpost&lt;/a&gt;, we had some pre-conference workshops to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io&#34;&gt;DevOps Gathering&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday the 23rd March. They took place in the the campus of the Ruhr University in Bochum (RUB).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sponsors&#34;&gt;SPONSORS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the main conference day on Friday and Saturday we organized a special location in the ruhr area: The G Data Campus, a location with a over a 100 years of history (If you like to read the full history about this location - you can find it &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gdata.de/news/g-data-grundstein-fuer-expansion-in-bochum-gelegt&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, unfortunately only in German) . &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gdata.de/&#34;&gt;G Data Software company&lt;/a&gt;, a german IT security pioneer, was our this year location and conference party sponsor. At this point - once again a BIG THANK YOU to G Data for being our supportive sponsor!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course - We don’t want to miss all the other sponsors of the DevOps Gathering 2017:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;as already mentioned - &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/#gdata&#34;&gt;G DATA&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bee42.com&#34;&gt;bee42&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/#setlog&#34;&gt;Setlog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/#wifo&#34;&gt;Bochum Wirtschaftsentwicklung&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/#openknowledge&#34;&gt;open knowledge&lt;/a&gt; as a t-shirt sponsor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/#host1plus&#34;&gt;Host1Plus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/#codecentric&#34;&gt;codecentric&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/#9elements&#34;&gt;9elements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/#aufgeweckt&#34;&gt;agentur aufgeweckt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/#dpunkt&#34;&gt;dpunkt verlag&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/#styracosoft&#34;&gt;styracosoft&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find all information about our sponsors on out conference website: &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/&#34;&gt;https://devops-gathering.io/sponsors/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-program-talks-and-speakers&#34;&gt;THE PROGRAM, TALKS AND SPEAKERS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One evening before the conference days, on Thursday after the workshops day, we prepared the location at the G Data Campus and organized the last stuff and prepared everything, what we had to do: The Check-In Desk, the Sponsors Area, the Conference Room and so on. We were so excited about the first official conference day! :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the morning of the first main conference day the organizer &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/PRossbach&#34;&gt;Peter Roßbach&lt;/a&gt; warmly welcomed all attendees, sponsors and speakers with some key facts about the Conference and of course with information about the upcoming IT Revolution, about Docker, about organisation transformation and technology shift, and all the other topics that we entered in our program and talks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We assembled such a great &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/#speakers&#34;&gt;speaker line up&lt;/a&gt; and welcomed so many Docker Captains (three), international and national experts on the first day of the DevOps Gathering - As you can see in our following &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/#talks&#34;&gt;schedule (March 24th)&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“How we run Kubernetes in Kubernetes, aka Kubeception” &lt;strong&gt;by Timo Derstappen (Giant Swarm)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Docker Container Loading” &lt;strong&gt;by Roland Huss (RedHat)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Docker Orchestration and Swarming” &lt;strong&gt;by Peter Roßbach (bee42 solutions)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“One year monitoring a small startup with Prometheus: lessons learned” &lt;strong&gt;by Maykel Moya (ShuttleCloud)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Build and deploy multiarch Linux and Windows Container images” &lt;strong&gt;by Docker Captain Stefan Scherer (SEAL Systems)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Intel and ARM, let Kubernetes rule them all!” &lt;strong&gt;by the talented Lucas Käldström&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Make load-balancing great again with Træfik!” &lt;strong&gt;by Emile Vauge and Manuel Laufenberg (both working for traefik.io)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Getting the most out of your containerized database” &lt;strong&gt;by Claus Matzinger (crate.io)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keynote: “DevOps is not enough – towards a DevOps ecosystem” &lt;strong&gt;by Uwe Friedrichsen (codecentric)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the full schedule including the abstracts, more pictures and the slides of the talks on our website: &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/#talks&#34;&gt;https://devops-gathering.io/#talks&lt;/a&gt;. Just click on the talk you like to see and you will find all further information on the subsite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-recorded-all-sessions-for-you&#34;&gt;We recorded ALL sessions for you&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who think slides are not enough or for those who hadn’t the chance and time to participate in this special community conference, we have some good news for you: All talks of the conference day were recorded! We&amp;rsquo;ll upload all conference talks including the slides within the next weeks via our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCQZcFFlmKBBAhvSupNTm2tw&#34;&gt;DevOps Gathering Youtube Channel&lt;/a&gt;! Besides that we&amp;rsquo;ll put them of course directly on our website &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io&#34;&gt;devops-gathering.io&lt;/a&gt;. You want to be the first to know about the uploaded talks? Then…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;subscribe our youtube channel to see them directly when they’re online: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCQZcFFlmKBBAhvSupNTm2tw&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCQZcFFlmKBBAhvSupNTm2tw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;just subscribe for our bee42 newsletter here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/ghGIxV&#34;&gt;https://goo.gl/ghGIxV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and follow us on twitter via DevOps Gathering and bee42 solutions for the hot news: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/DevOpsGathering&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/DevOpsGathering&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bee42solutions&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/bee42solutions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;d like to read and know what happened at the Open Space on the last day of the Conference DevOps Gathering, then read the next blogpost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;impressions-of-the-devops-gathering-conference-day&#34;&gt;Impressions of the DevOps Gathering Conference Day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt; HEAD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog//dogr_conference/DevOps-Gathering-2017-Conference.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;devops-gathering-conference-attendees-https-bee42-com-images-blog-dogr-conference-devops-gathering-2017-jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/DevOps-Gathering-2017.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference Attendees&#34; /&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog//dogr_conference/DevOps-Gathering-2017-Conference.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/images/blog/dogr_conference/DevOps-Gathering-2017.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference Attendees&#34; /&gt;
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; origin/master&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/claus-matzinger-devops-gathering.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference Claus Matzinger&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/DevOps-Gathering-Peter-Rossbach.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference Peter Roßbach&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/DevOps-Gathering-Introduction.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference Introduction&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/dieter-reuter-lucas-kaeldtroem-devops-gathering.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference Docker Captain and Lucas Käldström&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/Docker-Captain-at-DevOps-Gathering.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference Docker Captain&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/Docker-Captain-and-Lucas-Kaeldstroem-DevOps-Gathering.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference Introduction&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/docker-captain-stefan-scherer-devops-gathering.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference Stefan Scherer&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt; HEAD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;devops-gathering-conference-attendees-https-bee42-com-images-blog-dogr-conference-teilnehmer-devops-gathering-jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/teilnehmer-devops-gathering.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference attendees&#34; /&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;ihttps://bee42.com/mages/blog/dogr_conference/teilnehmer-devops-gathering.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference attendees&#34; /&gt;
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; origin/master&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/lucas-kaeldstroem-devops-gathering-talk.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference Stage&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/peter-rossbach-roland-huss-devops-gathering-stage.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/teilnehmer-frage-devops-gathering.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference participants&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/peter-rossbach-roland-huss-maven-birthday.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference Docker Maven PlugIn&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/teilnehmer-frage-runde-devops-gathering.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference Teilnehmer&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/timo-derstappen-lachen-on-stage.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference Fun&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/teilnehmer-fragerunde-devops-gathering.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference questions&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/traefik-at-DevOps-Gathering-2017.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference traefik&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/traefik-at-devops-gathering.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference traefik&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dogr_conference/Uwe-Friedrichsen-codecentric-DevOps-Gathering.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps Gathering Conference &#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevOps Gathering Workshops</title>
      <link>https://bee42.com/blog/devops-gathering-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bee42.com/blog/devops-gathering-workshops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On March 23th we organized some very interesting Docker Workshops as pre-conference workshops to the conference &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/&#34;&gt;DevOps Gathering 2017&lt;/a&gt;! The attendess had the chance to learn from Docker Captains and experts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to set up an automated container building pipeline with GitLab/CI?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to build and deploy multi-arch Linux and Windows Container images?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to operate Java applications with Docker and Kubernetes?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to setup Docker Swarm cluster on AWS?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to develop, test and deploy software in Docker using tools such as Spring-Boot and Gradle?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dealing with new possibilities of software development and deployment with DevOps tools like Docker, Kubernetes and Cloud-Computing was practically addressed at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/#workshops&#34;&gt;DevOps Gathering pre-conference workshops&lt;/a&gt;. The attendees had the chance to learn from DevOps experts from companies like RedHat, styracosoft, AutoScout24, Seal Systems and of course bee42 solutions. We are proud to have nearly all german Docker Captains (three!) hold workshops and shared their deep Docker tips and tricks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the GitLab/CI Workshop, &lt;strong&gt;Niclas Mietz from bee42 solutions&lt;/strong&gt;, showed in the first stage the easy use of GitLab. After this the attendees got an instructed way to build a CI and CD pipeline to deliver her first container on a system. The next stage was to get a deeper knowledge of the architecture and the concepts of the GitLab/CI ecosystem. After finishing these both stages, a new Microservice project got imported and a CI pipeline was built for this Microservice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stefan Scherer&lt;/strong&gt; from Seal Systems and &lt;strong&gt;Dieter Reuter&lt;/strong&gt; from bee42 solutions, &lt;strong&gt;both Docker Captains&lt;/strong&gt;, showed new features of the Windows Servers 2016 and its integration to run Docker and Windows Containers. By pulling Docker images from the Docker Hub and run it on the Docker Engine, attendees learned to configure TCP/IP ports and volumes to connect running container to the outside world.
Successfully taking an application based upon microservices and dockerize it into a set of Windows containers, was the goal of the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roland Huss from RedHat&lt;/strong&gt; showed his attendees how to add two connected Microservices based on Wildly-Swarm and Spring-Boot, Roland demonstrated live the creation of Docker images to Maven builds and how to simplify integration tests by Docker. Running and orchestrating these images on Kubernetes was the second part of the workshop. The integration with the fabric8-maven-plugin was shown in more detail. Finally, the attendees got a good overview how to put several Java applications in containers and how to orchestrate them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Philipp Garbe from AutoScout24&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Docker Captain&lt;/strong&gt;, showed in his workshop how to run Docker Containers on AWS. In his hands-on workshop he started to guide his attendees through the basic setups with all local requirements and the immutable infrastructure with CloudFormation. Further the attendees learned to run Docker on EC2 (VMs) and how to scale with AutoScaling Groups. Finally, with the setup of Docker Swarm clusters on AWS, everyone was able to deploy and update applications based on Docker Compose v3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kevin Wittek and Matthias Rottländer, both from styracosoft&lt;/strong&gt;, took the attendees through the complete development lifecycle of a simple microservice, using familiar tools such as Spring-Boot and Gradle. Based on practical examples the workshop started with running Spring-Boot Apps inside a Docker container and building Spring-Boot Docker images using Gradle. Using containers for unit and integration tests in Spring-Boot Apps with Spock and Docker and deploying and configuring Spring-Boot microservices using docker-compose, gave an insight to new possibilities of up to date development and testing environments&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the full schedule and agenda, all workshops and talks of the DevOps Gathering 2017 on our website &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io/&#34;&gt;devops-gathering.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you once again to all our Speakers, Docker Daptains, Experts and of course the Attendees! We are looking forward to the next DevOps Gathering and Workshops!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bee42/DevOps Gathering Crew&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4th Docker Birthday Party in the Ruhr Area</title>
      <link>https://bee42.com/blog/4th-Docker-Birthday/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bee42.com/blog/4th-Docker-Birthday/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/all_cakes_docker.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Cakes Worldwide&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We love to use Docker in our daily business, that&amp;rsquo;s also why we organize a week after the Docker Birthday the &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io&#34;&gt;DevOps Gathering&lt;/a&gt; (March 23 - 25, 2017) in Bochum, a conference for Docker container, Kubernetes, DevOps and more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that was NO excuse not to celebrate the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.docker.com/2017/02/announcing-docker-birthday-4-spreading-docker-love/&#34;&gt;4th Docker Birthday&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/birthday_wal_bee42.png&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Whale bee42&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;first-of-all-a-big-thank-you-to&#34;&gt;First of all..a BIG THANK YOU to&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;strong&gt;Karen Bajza&lt;/strong&gt; for spreading the Docker love and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.docker.com/2017/02/announcing-docker-birthday-4-spreading-docker-love/&#34;&gt;4th birthday vibes&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tech.zalando.com/?gh_src=4n3gxh1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zalando&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for sponsoring this Docker Birthday Party in Dortmund and making this event possible!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.setlog.com/de/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setlog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; also for sponsoring this  birthday meetup!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bee42.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bee42&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for sponsoring the awesome, big (!!!) and delicious Docker Container Cake! (you can have a look below, there are a lot of pictures)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;our gorgeous baker of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.baeckerei-mohr.de/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bakery Mohr&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in Dortmund - thank you for the great cake and the details!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;our mentors &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/PRossbach&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/solidnerd&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Niclas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jans0510&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Albert &amp;amp; Dima&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dimi8795&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dimitry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Kiview&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kevin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  - thank you for your support and expertise!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;Docker Captains &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/marcosnils&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marcos Lilljedahl&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/xetorthio&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jonathan Leibiusky&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for creating play-with-docker, a fun and easy way to work through these labs and courses!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-facts&#34;&gt;KEY FACTS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we tell and report you about OUR 4th Docker Birthday celebration, we&amp;rsquo;d like to give you some key facts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;Docker in 80+ countries!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;over 154 Docker Birthday #4 celebrations were announced for this year!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;over 650 tweets about this year Docker Birthday celebration!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;6000+ RSVPs worldwide!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;700+ Docker mentors worldwide!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;take-aways-of-the-docker-birthday-last-week&#34;&gt;TAKE AWAYS of the Docker Birthday last week:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;slides of this Docker Birthday MeetUp: &lt;a href=&#34;https://speakerdeck.com/rossbachp/docker-birthday-introduction-meetup-bochum-dortmund&#34;&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/rossbachp/docker-birthday-introduction-meetup-bochum-dortmund&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;discount code for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://devops-gathering.io&#34;&gt;DevOps Gathering&lt;/a&gt; in Bochum, Germany (30% off with the code: &lt;strong&gt;docker30&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;discount code for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://2017.dockercon.com/&#34;&gt;DockerCon&lt;/a&gt; in Austin,TX USA (30% off with the code: &lt;strong&gt;BDAY4&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kevin &amp;amp; Ali from &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/adessoAG&#34;&gt;adesso&lt;/a&gt; won tickets (2-Day-Passes) for the DevOps Gathering!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;our-docker-birthday-party&#34;&gt;OUR DOCKER BIRTHDAY PARTY&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Docker Birthday #4 was celebrated at Zalando on the 16th March 2017. We brought both Community Groups from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/de-DE/Docker-Bochum/&#34;&gt;Bochum&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/de-DE/Docker-Dortmund/&#34;&gt;Dortmund&lt;/a&gt; together to celebrate this event. To celebrate together we warmly welcomed newcomers and the already known Docker friends! We provided free Docker labs and courses to learn about Docker in a fun and inviting way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had hands-on with self-paced tutorials for every experience level from absolute beginners to professionals (with focus on beginners to intermediate).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The agenda for the Docker Birthday Party was as the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;18:00 - 18:30: Come together for dinner (Pizza &amp;amp; Drinks)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;18:30 - 18:45: Salutation and introductory words&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;18:45 - 20:45: Mentoring sessions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20:45 - 22:00: Celebration with drinks and a very special cake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a little schedule to finish all things we want to do. Our Meetup started with Pizza and Drinks to get strong enough for all problems that we wanted to resolve. After this &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/PRossbach&#34;&gt;Peter Rossbach&lt;/a&gt;, our Docker expert, held an short introduction about Docker and the Docker Birthday courses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/Introduction_DockerBirthday_Peter_Rossbach.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Introduction by Peter Rossbach&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With ending of the introduction all participants built small groups to handle the courses in a timeframe of two hours. In some groups there were dedicated Mentors for the courses, because Mentors likes as well to learn new stuff and take challenges :) . And the other groups could get help from Mentors on-demand or Mentors ask them if they can help on the problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/DockerBirthday_Working_in_Groups.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Labs and courses&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After our timeframe ended, we missed some important step: The Docker Birthday Cake - The most important part of the evening!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looked so small but trust us - the cake was 20 centimeters high, 20 kg heavy and it was filled with raspberry (pi, hihi) creme and chocolate!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/Docker_Birthday_Cake_Container.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Cake&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After our stomach hurted from the delicious cake and the little sugar overdose, we took our chance make a selfie with some people:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/Selfie_DockerBirthday_Party.png&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Selfie&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next year we want to repeat this great event. We hope that you can join us as well to celebrate this day! :-)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/DockerBirthday_Webcam_Video.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Celebration&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/docker-birthday-cake-full.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Moby Dock&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/docker-birthday-celebration-sitting-labs-fun.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Docker Labs&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/docker_birthday_party_meetup.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday MeetUp&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/docker-birthday-cake-details-gopher.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Gopher Cake&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/DockerBirthday_fun.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Fun&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/Docker_Whale_Lego_DockerBirthday.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Moby Dock&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/docker-birthday-cake-details-mini-cake.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Gopher Cake&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/docker-birthday-celebration-fun.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Party MeetUp&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/docker-birthday-container-cake-details.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Cake Details&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/Docker-Birthday-Discussion.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Group Discussion&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/docker-birthday-labs-groups.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Group MeetUp&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bee42.com/images/blog/dockerbirthday/docker-birthday-party-cake.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Birthday Cake the day after&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>